TRACEY HEMPHILL-WRIGHT

Phone 616-828-2300 Grand Rapids, MI Email:twright48@email.davenport.edu
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/traceyhemphillwright/

Creative and detailed-oriented software engineer with a diverse technical background with a priority for customer-focused service. Bringing experience in cross-platform mobile development/support and frontend and backend web development with their associated databases and API's.

TECHNICAL TOOLBOX

- iOS/Android Development
- App Store Publishing
- SQL, Git, JSON
- Sketch, Adobe Creative Suite
- C#, Xamarin, Flutter, Swift, Java
- Visual Studio, Xcode
- Scaled Agile, Jira, GitHub
- AWS, Docker, MS SQL Server
- React JS, HTML, CSS
- Firebase Analytics, WordPress/REST API
- Mac OS, Windows, Linux/UNIX

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

OUR DAILY BREAD MINISTRIES Grand Rapids, MI

Jul 2017-Present

- Develop/Maintain iOS, Android apps using: Visual Studio/Xamarin, Xcode, Google Play Console, Apple Developer, iTunes Connect, WordPress REST API, Facebook Developer, Amazon Web Services, Google Analytics for Firebase Xamarin and Jira
- Provided bug fixes and project work for OurDailyBread, My Utmost and Pao Diario mobile apps for iOS and Android
- Developed in a Scrum environment: Groomed user stories, participated in PI planning, retros, and demos
- Performed requirements gathering for iOS and Android apps
- Maintained ODB, My Utmost, ODB 365 Teen, and Pao Diario apps for iOS and Android
- Managed user testing for beta apps, in iTunesConnect, Amazon Developer and GooglePlay Console
- Published apps and app updates to iTunes Connect, Google Play Console and Amazon Developer
- Provided assistance to YMI app and ODB 365 Teen app consulting teams
- Provided documentation to help track, diagnose issues and support ODB's digital devotionals using lira and Confluence
- Provided development, release, maintenance, and sunsetting for the Pao Diario yearly devotional app
- Provided development to localize Sinhala and Afrikaans languages to ODB app and in the app stores
- Provided timely and clear communication with customers and colleges throughout various offices of Our Daily Bread Ministries

WEB DEVELOPER/SOLUTIONS ENGINEER

Jan 2016-Sep 2016

ACI COMMUNICATIONS
Seattle WA (Remote Gran

Seattle, WA (Remote, Grand Rapids)

Charged with developing and re-designing, company website and content for acicomms.com. Collaborated with Product Management, HR, Sales, Marketing and Engineering Teams, via team meetings, email, phone, and Skype to develop ways to educate and engage customers, regarding the ACI Broadband Amplifier product line, on acicomms.com.

- Customized website functionality and appearance using php, html, css, WordPress.
- Increased company website's flexibility/control/access.
- Created new avenues to engage external customers on the website.
- Designed RMA return process for acicomms.com.
- Provided visual content for magazine Ad.

APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER ANALYST, ASSOC.

April 2014 - Jan 2016

SPECTRUM HEALTH Grand Rapids, MI

- Provided Frontend and Backend development and support by providing enhancements, bug fixes and
 customer small project requests for various internal clinical web applications and the external Priority
 Health and MyHealth website and iOS mobile app. Provided customer-focused service to clinical and
 insurance customers
- Debugged, tested and verified web application modifications using various languages such as C#, JQuery, AngularJS, Perl, JavaScript and database queries.
- Debugged, tested and verified mobile app modifications using various languages such as JQuery, AngularJS, git, github, PhoneGap and database queries.
- Analyzed software issues, made code changes, tested and implement changes using a variety of software development toolkits, programming languages, Tortoise SVN, Git, Github, and database tools.
- Gathered business requirements into detailed technical specifications for web applications, and maintained triage documents.
- Performed developer code reviews.

INFORMATION SYSTEMS INTERN

May 2013 - Dec 2013

SPECTRUM HEALTH Grand Rapids, MI

- Supported and assisted clinical customers, insurance customers and patients with troubleshooting, software, hardware and various issues using remote access, Citrix Receiver, Service Desk, Remote access, Epic Production and Triage docs.
- Mentored and trained colleagues on the use Spectrum health's IIVE social business platform.
- Used Lean principles to gather feedback from clinicians at various Grand Rapids Hospitals and presented to colleagues at Help Desk team meetings, to improve service.
- Create blog content, graphics and interactive content on custom JIVE webpages.

WEB/DATABASE INTERN

Jan 2013 - April 2013

FOREST HILLS PUBLIC SCHOOLS Grand Rapids, MI

- Assisted personnel at the Instructional Office with internal web site solutions.
- Created and edited internal web pages for Instruction Office at Forest Hills Public Schools.

ORDER FULLFILLMENT

Aug 2004 – Feb 2005

MANPOWER Grand Rapids, MI

• Order fulfillment, inventory, packing and shipping customer orders for Family Christian Stores.

ENGINEERING TECHNICIAN

Sep 1994 - Oct 1999

- Tested, and repaired high performance broadband amplifier products and optical nodes for a major cable television and telecommunications manufacturer.
- Assembled, modified, and performed prototype testing of fiber optic nodes systems and experimental circuitry, from sketches and schematics, using various tools and electronic test equipment.
- Troubleshot and repaired failed units. Analyzed, interpreted, and formatted test data using various computer applications.
- Developed technical reports; documenting specs, testing simulations and test results, for presentation to upper management and customers.

ELECTRONICS TECHNICIAN

Aug 1982 - Oct 1987

UNITED STATES NAVY San Diego, CA

- Provided complete telecommunications support at various U.S. Naval Bases on the West Coast and Philippines.
- Troubleshot, repaired, and maintained Microwave Radio communication systems and Encrypted Communications systems throughout San Diego CA and in Bataan Philippines, providing 100% communications readiness.
- Repaired all equipment to component level.
- Remain on call to quickly analyze and troubleshoot wide variety of technical problems.
- Provided bi-weekly process and safety training to fellow colleagues.
- Performed preventive and corrective maintenance on all equipment and maintained accurate records.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

BACHELOR'S OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS, DAVENPORT UNIVERSITY, GRAND RAPIDS, MI

Certified SAFe® 4 Practitioner, May 2019

Microsoft Server and Admin, New Horizons, Grand Rapids MI

CISCO ROUTING AND SWITCHING NEW HORIZONS, GRAND RAPIDS MI

COMPUTER NETWORKING AND SECURITY NEW HORIZONS, GRAND RAPIDS MI

ASSOCIATES, ELECTRONICS TECHNOLOGY, OLYMPIC COLLEGE, BREMERTON, WA

CRYPTO COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, UNITED STATES NAVY, VALLEJO, CA

ADVANCED ELECTRONICS TECHNOLOGY, UNITED STATES NAVY, GREAT LAKES, IL

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

BITCAMP – INSTRUCTOR 2014, 2015 HTTP://BITCAMP.SOFTWAREGR.ORG

Grand Rapids Women's Resource Center - Q&A Panelist, 2015 $\mbox{\em http://www.grwrc.org}$

HOUR OF CODE – INSTRUCTOR AT KENTWOOD P.S. EXPLORER ELEMENTARY, 2015 HTTPS://HOUROFCODE.COM